# Mike Woodcock | Economist

Street 119a No. 70g-28 - Bogotá, Colombia

☐ 312 553 8143 • ☑ mikewoodcockc@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Economist studying mathematics, coordinator and researcher on the research group on institutional and evolutionist economics, coordinator on the study group of artificial intelligence, researcher on the research groups of Artificial Life and the Observatory of Mobility and Transport from the National University of Colombia, moreover working with the Legislative Team of the Senator and Presidential Candidate Claudia Lopez.

# **Experience**

Research Group on Mobility and Transport

Researcher

National University of Colombia

Mar 2017 - present

Research Group on Institutional and Evolutionist Economics

Coordinator and Researcher

National University of Colombia

Jan 2017 - present

Senator Claudia López's Legislative Team
Congress of the Republic of Colombia
Economic Assistant
Dec 2016 - Jun 2017

Research Group on Artificial Life
Researcher

National University of Colombia
Sep 2016 - Present

Study Group on Artificial Intelligence

Coordinator

National University of Colombia

Aug 2016 - present

Dynamic Modeling Subject

Assistant professor

National University of Colombia

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

Static Modeling Subject

Assistant professor

Study Group on Distributed Apps

National University of Colombia

Jan 2013 - Jul 2014

National University of Colombia

Coordinator

National University of Colombia

Jun 2014 - Jan 2015

High-level Dialogue on Sustainable Cities

National University of Colombia

University of Colombia

Study Group on Distributed Apps

University of Colombia

Financial Market Analysis Unit

Assistant Professor.

National University of Colombia

Jan 2013 - Jan 2014

Volunteer-Personal Assistant of the Director of the Chinese Committee, Lian He.

## **Education**

National University of Colombia
Undergraduate, Mathematics. GPA: 4.4

National University of Colombia
Undergraduate, Economics. GPA: 4.3

2015 - present

Aug 2014

2014 - 2017

National University of Colombia

Undergraduate (Not finished), Business Administration. GPA: 4.4

2012 - 2014

### **Projects**

Senator Claudia López's Legislative Team

 Analysis of current and historic sentiment towards an specific agent based on twitter data

Mar 2017 - Present

Study Group on Artificial Intelligence

 Autonomous Agent for patterns recognition in stochastic variables of high volatility applied to financial variables with the use of AI National University of Colombia

May 2017 - Present

Research Group on Mobility and Transport

 Policy Impact Evaluation on Taxis and Uber Services in Bogota: A Complex Simulation Approach National University of Colombia

Jan 2017 - Present

Personal project

TruequeGamer.com game exchange platform

May 2016 - Present

Personal project

mikew.io personal web site

Dec 2015 - Present

Study Group on Distributed Apss

SomosUn.com study plan manager app

National University Of Colombia Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

#### **Articles**

 An Approach About Monetary Policy Risk Balance In Colombia: A Multivariate Analysis Based On Time Series Econógrafos No. 85

Dec 2016

Basic Analysis of The Hex Game Econógrafos No. 80

Aug 2015

# **Honors / Achievements**

#### Colfuturo

Colfuturo Loan-Scholarship for Master Studies.

Mar 2017

Colfuturo

Member of Young talent program of Colfuturo (Semillero de Talentos)

Jan 2016

National University of Colombia

Scholarship [5 times]. Payment Exemption of the Registration Rights.

Granted by the Engineering Department, Economic Sciences Department and by the Science Department

National University of Colombia

Honor enrollment
Granted by the Economic Sciences Department

Jan 2012

# Languages

o English: C1 (IELTS 2017)

o French: B1 (National University of Colombia).

o German: A2 (National University of Colombia)

o Spanish: Native Speaker

# **Technical Skills**

- o Programming language
  - Python
  - C++Java
  - Javascript
  - STATA
- Technologies
  - React.js
  - Angular.js
  - Git

- RATS
- R
- Matlab
- Netlogo
- Django
- Google App Engine
- Amazon Web Services

#### **Interests**

Playing piano, listening to music, jogging, using my bike, psychology and reading are some of my interests. But more important that just specific interests, I can say in general that I like trying new experiences, going to new places and learning different stuff whenever there is a chance.